<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/concept.dtd">
<concept id="preparing_for_d2c">
	<title>Configuring the publishing options</title>
	<prolog>
		<author>Lisa J Dyer</author>
		<copyright>
			<copyryear year="2005-2009"/>
			<copyrholder>Lombardi Software, Inc.</copyrholder>
		</copyright>
		<critdates>
			<created date="March 1, 2007"/>
			<revised modified="August 1, 2008" golive="September 2, 2008" status="changed"/>
			<revised modified="February 15, 2009" golive="February 27, 2009" status="changed"/>
		</critdates>
		<metadata>
			<audience experiencelevel="general" type="user" job="planning"/>
		</metadata>
	</prolog>
	<conbody>
		<p>The DITA2Confluence tool provides configuration options for how DITA XML content is published to the wiki. Most of these options are configured in the 
<codeph>confluence.content.xml</codeph> file. Each DITA map equals one content module. For each content module, you create an entry in the 
<codeph>confluence.content.xml</codeph> file with required and optional attributes. </p>
		<p>Some options are intended for use in testing environments only, to aid development and debugging. </p>
		<p>The <codeph>confluence.config.xml</codeph> file governs the wiki environment settings at the system level. Usually, setting up the environment is a one-time 
configuration task.</p>
		<section>
			<title>Configuring where and how to publish</title>
			<p>The following options are configured in the <codeph>confluence.config.xml</codeph> file, which resides under the root directory of your DITA2Confluence 
installation.</p>
			<table>
				<tgroup cols="3">
					<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
					<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2"/>
					<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3"/>
					<thead>
						<row>
							<entry>Element</entry>
							<entry>Attribute</entry>
							<entry>Usage</entry>
						</row>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<row>
							<entry>config</entry>
							<entry/>
							<entry>Parent element with the following attributes for describing the wiki environment.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>bindingaddress</entry>
							<entry>Specify the IP address for the wiki instance to which you are publishing. In most cases, this is the same value as the URL.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>url</entry>
							<entry>Specify the full Web address to the wiki instance to which you are publishing.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>username</entry>
							<entry>Specify a user who has site-level administrative permissions to access the target wiki instance.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>password</entry>
							<entry>Specify the password for the user. You can also supply the password from the command-line console.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>ditaxslfilename</entry>
							<entry>Default XSL transformation config file. Optionally specify a custom XSL file.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>dtddir</entry>
							<entry>Folder path or URL to DTD specifications. This can be the absolute path, public URI or path relative to routine installation folder. By 
default, the convenience copies of the DITA Open Toolkit DTDs are used. Optionally specify a path to your copy of the DTDs or the public URI. 
Note that when referencing the public URI, you must be connected online, and the processing times are significantly longer.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>toxslfilename</entry>
							<entry>XSL transformation rules for the Table of Contents page which is created on the wiki when the <codeph>generatetoc</codeph> attribute for a 
content module is set to <codeph>true</codeph>. Optionally specify a custom XSL file.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>enablesortid</entry>
							<entry>
								<p>Optional Boolean attribute for programmatically assigning sort IDs to the published topics based on the hierarchy in the DITA map(s). Sort 
IDs in conjunction with custom macros enable you to implement navigational constructs such as dynamic tree views. </p>
								<p>When using <codeph>enablesortid</codeph>, you need to also set the ID range for each of your content modules using the 
<codeph>sortidstart</codeph> and <codeph>sortidend</codeph> attributes in the <codeph>confluence.content.xml</codeph> file. </p>
							</entry>
						</row>
					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</table>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Configuring what to publish</title>
			<p>The following options are configured in the <codeph>confluence.content.xml</codeph> file, which resides under the root directory of your DITA2Confluence 
installation. All elements and attributes are required unless specified as optional.</p>
			<table>
				<tgroup cols="3">
					<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
					<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2"/>
					<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3"/>
					<thead>
						<row>
							<entry>Element</entry>
							<entry>Attribute</entry>
							<entry>Usage</entry>
						</row>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<row>
							<entry>contentroot</entry>
							<entry/>
							<entry>Parent element that contains one or more <codeph>module</codeph> elements. A <codeph>contentroot</codeph> element uniquely identifies the 
location of the DITA XML source. For each source path, create one <codeph>contentroot</codeph> element with an unlimited number of 
<codeph>module</codeph> elements.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>path</entry>
							<entry>Absolute path to the root directory of the DITA XML source for one or more content modules.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>module</entry>
							<entry/>
							<entry>Element for declaring a content module (a module equals a DITA map).</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>folder</entry>
							<entry>Name of the folder in which the DITA map folder resides.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>spacekey</entry>
							<entry>Identifier of the space to which you are publishing your content module(s). The spacekey value can be dynamically generated based on 
ditaval rules, but most often you'll want to specify it explicitly. The spacekey syntax is governed by the wiki engine, which throws exceptions 
for illegal characters.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>ditamap</entry>
							<entry>Name of the target DITA map, excluding the file extension. The constructor expects a DITA map to reside in a <codeph>ditamap</codeph> 
folder. </entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>comment</entry>
							<entry>Optional attribute for adding a comment to new and updated topics. By default this value is empty (no comment is added). A comment must be 
inside quotation marks. You can also specify a comment from command line.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>ditaval</entry>
							<entry>Optional name of the <codeph>*.ditava</codeph>l file, which sets rules for excluding or including content based on DITA XML markup. If a 
<codeph>ditaval</codeph> file exists for a content module, you can choose to omit the spacekey value in the 
<codeph>confluence.content.xm</codeph>l file. This causes the build process to create the space dynamically based on the ditaval file name. This 
is useful when publishing complex information products dynamically based on metadata structures (e.g. one information set for "novice" and 
another for "expert"). In most cases, though, you'll want to specify the target spacekey explicitly.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>generatetoc</entry>
							<entry>Optional Boolean attribute (true or false) for generating a Table of Contents page on the wiki based on the DITA map hierarchy. Designed 
for development and debugging scenarios. </entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>labels</entry>
							<entry>Optional attribute for adding one or more labels to the topics in a content module. </entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>parentpagetitle</entry>
							<entry>Optional attribute for specifying a parent page for the topics in a content module. A parent page can be an original wiki page, or it can 
be a topic in a DITA map. Designed for creating "landing page" structures that aid content discovery and navigation. </entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>processcontentlabels</entry>
							<entry>Optional attribute for adding one or more labels (tags) to new and updated topics based on metadata in the DITA XML source. Specifically, 
the <codeph>&lt;prodname></codeph> and <codeph>&lt;vrm></codeph> values in the <codeph>&lt;metadata></codeph> element are used to construct the 
label. Disabled (false) by default. You can also specify one or more labels from command line using the <codeph>labels</codeph> attribute. 
</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>sortidend</entry>
							<entry>Required when <codeph>enablesortid=true</codeph> in the <codeph>confluence.config.xml</codeph> file. The <codeph>sortidstart</codeph> and 
<codeph>sortidend</codeph> attributes specify the numeric range within which sort IDs are generated for a content module (for example, 
<codeph>sortidstart=0, sortidend=250</codeph>). Each range can be different, just ensure that the ranges do not overlap. The total maximum range 
for all content modules on a wiki is <codeph>9999</codeph>.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>sortidstart</entry>
							<entry>Required when <codeph>enablesortid=true</codeph> in the <codeph>confluence.config.xml</codeph> file. The <codeph>sortidstart</codeph> and 
<codeph>sortidend</codeph> attributes specify the numeric range within which sort IDs are generated for a content module (for example, 
<codeph>sortidstart=0, sortidend=250</codeph>). The total maximum range for all content modules on a wiki is <codeph>9999</codeph>.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>spacehomepage</entry>
							<entry>Optional attribute for specifying an existing home page for the target space. If this is not specified, and the 
<codeph>generatetoc</codeph> attribute is set to <codeph>true</codeph>, a Table of Contents page is created as the home page, replacing any 
existing home page. Therefore, be careful when using <codeph>generatetoc</codeph>. If generatetoc is set to false, topics are published to the 
space root by default. To publish topics as children of existing wiki pages, use the <codeph>parentpagetitle</codeph> attribute.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>spacename</entry>
							<entry>Attribute for specifying the name of the space (not space key). If not specified, and the space is dynamically created, an error message 
will prompt you for a name value.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>wipecomments</entry>
							<entry>Optional attribute for deleting all comments from existing wiki pages in the DITA map scope. Disabled (false) by default. If you set this 
option to true, and then specify a value for the comment option (or specify it from command line), first all comments are deleted and then the 
new comment is added.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>wipelabels</entry>
							<entry>Optional attribute for deleting all labels from existing wiki pages in the DITA map scope. Disabled (false) by default. If you set this 
option to true, and then specify a value for one or more labels from command line, first all labels are deleted and then the new label(s) are 
added.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry>wipespace</entry>
							<entry>Optional attribute for deleting the target space. Disabled (false) by default. Designed for use in development environments, especially 
for dynamic publishing scenarios where spaces can proliferate in large numbers and become cumbersome to clean up. However, use this feature with 
extreme caution in production environments. You cannot restore a space after it is deleted unless you revert to a database backup, and normally 
some data loss occurs in doing so. </entry>
						</row>
					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</table>
		</section>
	</conbody>
</concept>
