<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "http://docs.oasis-open.org/dita/v1.1/OS/dtd/task.dtd">
<task id="publishing_d2c">
	<title>Publishing DITA XML content to the wiki</title>
	<prolog>
		<author>Lisa J Dyer</author>
		<copyright>
			<copyryear year="2005-2009"/>
			<copyrholder>Lombardi Software, Inc.</copyrholder>
		</copyright>
		<critdates>
			<created date="March 1, 2007"/>
			<revised modified="August 1, 2008" golive="September 2, 2008" status="changed"/>
			<revised modified="February 15, 2009" golive="February 27  2009" status="changed"/>
		</critdates>
		<metadata>
			<audience experiencelevel="general" type="user" job="using"/>
			<prodinfo>
				<prodname>DITA2Confluence</prodname>
				<vrmlist>
					<vrm version="1.2"/>
				</vrmlist>
			</prodinfo>
		</metadata>
	</prolog>
	<taskbody>
		<prereq>
			<p>Before you run the DITA2Confluence tool, ensure that you have met the system requirements, and prepared your DITA XML and wiki environments appropriately.</p>
			<p conref="d2c_system_overview.xml#d2c_system_overview/prereqs"/>
			<p conref="d2c_system_overview.xml#d2c_system_overview/prereqs_optional"/>
		</prereq>
		<context>
			<p>Run the DITA2Confluence tool from command line to publish your DITA XML content to the target wiki.</p>
		</context>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<cmd>Open the command-line interface and then navigate to the directory containing the <codeph>build.xml</codeph> file.</cmd>
			</step>
			<step>
				<cmd>Run the <codeph>ant</codeph> command to publish the target DITA XML content. </cmd>
				<stepxmp>
					<p>Basic command (publishes all modules configured in <codeph>confluence.content.xml</codeph>: <codeblock>ant</codeblock></p>
					<p>Advanced command example (publishes a single module with optional labels and a comment): <codeblock>ant -Dmodules=dita2confluence 
-Dpassword=mypassword -Dcomment="My first comment!" -Dlabels="1.2,dita2confluence,myspeciallabel"</codeblock></p>
				</stepxmp>
				<tutorialinfo>
					<table>
						<tgroup cols="2">
							<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
							<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2"/>
							<thead>
								<row>
									<entry>Parameter</entry>
									<entry>Usage</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody>
								<row>
									<entry>
										<codeph>ant</codeph>
									</entry>
									<entry>
										<p>Calls Ant to execute the dita2confluence target. An <ph conref="troubleshooting_d2c.xml#d2c_troubleshooting/no_ant"/> error 
indicates that the tool cannot find the Ant executable. <codeph>ANT_HOME</codeph> must be specified in your system path. Optionally, 
you can set it from command line for the current session only.</p>
										<p>An <ph conref="troubleshooting_d2c.xml#d2c_troubleshooting/no_jdk"/> indicates that the tool cannot find a supported version of 
the Java Runtime Environment (JRE). </p>
									</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry><codeph>-Dmodules</codeph></entry>
									<entry>Optional parameter to publish a single content module instead of all content modules configured in the 
<codeph>confluence.content.xml</codeph> file. You can also specify several modules as quoted comma-separated list: 
<codeph>-Dmodules="module1, module2"</codeph> </entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>
										<codeph>-Dpassword</codeph>
									</entry>
									<entry>
										<p>Optional parameter for specifying the password of the user who is accessing the Confluence system via the remote API. Overrides 
the password value configured in the <codeph>confluence.config.xml</codeph> file. Note that the input is not masked or encrypted.</p>
									</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>
										<codeph>-Dcomment</codeph>
									</entry>
									<entry>
										<p>Optional parameter for adding a comment to the topics in a content module. Note that you can also add a comment using the 
<codeph>comment</codeph> attribute for your content module. A comment specified at command line overrides a comment specified in the 
<codeph>confluence.content.xml</codeph> file. See <xref href="publish-with-comment_d2c.xml" type="concept" format="dita"/> for more 
information.</p>
									</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>
										<codeph>-Dlabels</codeph>
									</entry>
									<entry>
										<p>Optional parameter for adding one or more labels to the topics in a content module. You can also specify several labels as quoted 
comma-separated list: <codeph>-Dlabels="label_1, label_2"</codeph> Labels can also be auto-generated from metadata in the DITA XML 
source. See <xref href="publish-with-label_d2c.xml" type="concept" format="dita"/> for more information.</p>
									</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>
										<codeph>-Dgeneratetoc</codeph>
									</entry>
									<entry>
										<p>Optional session-wide parameter to force or forrbid generation of TOC page for all modules being imported in current session. 
Example: <codeph>-Dgeneratetoc=true|false</codeph> This parameter overrides 'generatetoc' setting specified in content file.</p>
									</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>
										<codeph>-Drebuild</codeph>
									</entry>
									<entry><i>For developers:</i> Optional Boolean parameter for compiling the Java classes to update the DITA2Confluence binary file 
(<codeph>lib/dita2confluence.jar</codeph>). If the binary file is not found, the build script automatically runs with the 
<codeph>-Drebuild</codeph> parameter enabled. If the source files are not found, and this parameter is set to true, the build fails. 
<note>You need to use the <codeph>-Drebuild</codeph> parameter only when changes have been made to the DITA2Confluence source code. This 
option performs the necessary compilation to produce the executable files.</note></entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
				</tutorialinfo>
			</step>
		</steps>
		<result>If no errors were encounted during the import operation, the tool reports a "Build successful" message in the command line output. Browse the target wiki 
space to verify that the expected content was successfully imported. If you encounter problems during the import, see "Troubleshooting".</result>
	</taskbody>
</task>
